# 甘肃·兰州
Lanzhou, Gansu Province
# 雪鱼现在在兰州 来兰州怎么能不吃牛兰州拉面呢
I’m in Lanzhou now and how can we skip the Lanzhou beef noodles
# 但是 你走在大街小巷上 你会发现
I found an interesting fact walking on the streets
# 他们的牌子上 没有一家写的是拉面馆
None of their signs say ramen
# 而都是牛肉面
They all say beef noodles
# 接下来我将去后面的牛肉面馆 看一看
Let’s have a look in this beef noodles restaurant behind
# 兰州的牛肉面 和我以前吃的有什么不同
What is different in Lanzhou’s beef noodles
# 牛肉面 8块钱一碗
Beef noodles are 8 yuan per bowl
# 你好 我要一碗牛肉面
Hi, I’d like a bowl of beef noodles
# 粗细 拌面的时候告诉他
Teel the staff how wide would you like the noodles
# 噢 好的 支付成功了
OK paid
# 看我后面这一米大锅里 他们炖了好多的牛肉
They are stewing so much beef in the meter-round pot behind me
# 这个汤就是待会牛肉面的底汤
The soup will be the base for the beef noodles
# 不过比起牛肉 我相信很多人和我一样
But I believe lots of people like myself are more interested in how they make the noodles
# 更想知道的是 在兰州 这个面条是怎么做成的
Especially how they make them here in Lanzhou
# 来 跟着我去拿面 这个过程就会看的明明白白
Come with me to get the noodles and let’s see
# 他们这边的牛肉面 讲究是一清 二白 三红 四绿 五黄
The standard for the beef noodles here are: clear, white, red, green and yellow
# 一清是指的 它的牛肉汤底很清
First the soup base needs to be clear
# 二白呢 是萝卜片白
Secondly, the radish slices are white
# 三红就是辣子红
Thirdly, the chili oil is red
# 四绿就是 蒜苗韭菜翠绿
Fourthly, the garlic greens and chives are green
# 五黄是因为面条里面加了蓬灰
Finally, the noodles are yellow because of the baking soda in them
# 所以呢 面条显示出微微的淡黄色
So that the noodles are a little yellow
# 我是没想到8块钱的牛肉面 是这么大的分量
I didn’t expect such big portion size for the 8 yuan price
# 除了拉面之外呢 还要了一份酱牛肉
I also ordered some spiced beef besides the noodles
# 这盘呢 就是牛腱子肉
This plate is the beef shank meat
# 此外呢 还加了一个卤蛋
Also a spiced egg
# 在当地 这个就叫 肉蛋双飞
It’s called the protein bomb here
# 这样的红油辣子 看起来都是很有食欲的
The chili oil seems so appetizing
# 这个面无敌 吃一口实在是太香了
The aroma is just amazing
# 面条并没有想象当中的 很有嚼头
The noodles are not as al dente as I expected
# 反而是咬一口 很容易咬断
It’s very easy to bite
# 吃的时候 你会觉得汤头浓郁 辣子香
The soup is really rich and the chili oil is so savory
# 你看 在这边吃了这么久 我都替你们尝了
Based on lots of food tasting in this trip
# 这边的辣子 虽然说 看起来 惊心动魄
The chili oil here seems very spicy
# 但是一点都不辣 而是增加了这种香味
But it’s not hot at all. It only adds the aroma
# 不过这半天 我们只看到了面条
We only saw noodles till now
# 牛肉面 不应该有肉吗
Shouldn’t the beef noodles come with beef?
# 找一找 有没有牛受的皮外伤的肉
Let’s see whether we can even find some beef grain
# 看来就是一碗8块钱的牛肉面 是没有牛肉的
It seems that the 8 yuan beef noodles don’t have beef
# 如果说 想吃牛肉就是得另加
If you want beef with it, you have to order specifically
# 要不呢 就是要酱牛肉 要不呢就是 要牛腱子肉
Or you can have the spiced beef or shank meat
# 酱牛肉：80块钱一斤
# 牛腱子肉：90块钱一斤
The spiced beef and shank meat are 80 and 90 yuan per jin (500 grams), respectively
# 吃的时候呢 要一两就可以 一两就是一碟
You can order one liang (50 grams) and that’s one small plate
# 我现在要把它变成 豪华牛肉面
Now let’s turn our noodles into the deluxe version
# 一般来说 都是实物与图片不符
Usually the food doesn’t seem the same from the ads
# 现在我们来还原图片
Now let’s get the ad version
# 还有一个蛋
One more egg
# 现在就是肉 蛋 面齐飞
Right now it’s the protein bomb with the carbohydrate bomb
# 我已经把肉盖住了面
The meat can cover the noodles
# 我觉得在座的各位的牛肉面 都没有我的豪华
My noodles are the most luxury than everybody else’s here
# 它是8块钱 9块钱 加上原来的8块钱
It’s 8 plus 9 plus 8 yuan
# 再加上一个蛋 一共是27块钱的牛肉面
Also with the egg, this bowl of beef noodles is 27 yuan in total
# 肉多也不是什么好事 挡住我吃面了
The only downside of this much meat is I can’t reach the noodles now
# 这句话好像是在炫耀
Sounds like bragging though
# 他们这边的面条 粗细是分很多种规格的
There’s a lot of sizes for noodles here
# 你想要哪种粗细 一定要在点面的时候告诉他
You need to tell them how wide you like your noodles when you order
# 像我点面的时候 就是直接问的 要粗的还是要细的
They only asked me wide or fine when I ordered
# 我说要细的 默认就是二细
I said fine and it went second fine by default
# 我后面的 还有的人点了韭叶宽 还有毛细
Guys behind me ordered chive wide and hair fine
# 你想要什么样规格的 师傅都能给你拉出来
The cook can make you any size you want
# 你看做拉面的小哥是很精瘦的
The cooks seem pretty lean
# 我本来以为 他应该是那种大块头
I thought they would be big
# 有这种大力气的人才能够拉得动那么长的面
So that they have enough strength to pull the big doughs
# 但实际上 做面的是一个比较精瘦的小哥
But actually he is pretty lean
# 他一直示意我们 过来拍啊 拍啊 表现欲很强
He was constantly telling us to come around and shoot, pretty outgoing
# 在兰州有句玩笑话叫
There is a local saying
# 兰州人 一天卖出的牛肉面
The beef noodles sold in Lanzhou in one day
# 能够把地球绕成一个毛线团子
Can twine the earth into a woolen ball
# 销量如此巨大 本地人的生活离不开它
The sales are huge and the locals cannot live without it
# 外地的朋友来到兰州 也一定会尝尝这碗面的味道
Tourists in Lanzhou also will definitely come and taste
# 吃完牛肉面 到黄河第一桥来看一看
After the beef noodles, let’s see the first Yellow River bridge
# 中山桥呢 是黄河上修建最早的铁桥
The Zhongshan bridge is the first bridge built across Yellow River
# 素有 天下黄河第一桥 的美称
So it’s called the first Yellow River bridge
# 在没有修建它之前 想跨越黄河 是件很困难的事情
It was very difficult to go across yellow river before building it
# 修建之后 不仅方便了两岸的经济生活
The building of the bridge not only make the people’s lives more convenient
# 也加强了兰州和西北地区的交流
It also strengthens the communications between Lanzhou and the Northwestern China
# 关  注
# 雪 鱼  探 店
Subscribe please 
>